<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="40">
<name>SECURITIES</name>
<section id="1002O_S0019" variety="S0019">
<name>ENGINE IMMOBILISER</name>
<ttl id="1002O_S0019_7301M_T00D1" variety="T00D1">
<name>ENGINE IMMOBILISER SYSTEM (w/ Smart Key System)</name>
<para id="RM000000PVN00BX" category="L" type-id="3001A" name-id="EI00J-10" from="200601">
<name>PRECAUTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000000PVN00BX_z0" proc-id="RM0250U___00008D700000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<step1>
<ptxt>PRECAUTIONS WHEN USING INTELLIGENT TESTER</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>When using the intelligent tester to troubleshoot the smart access system: Connect the intelligent tester to the DLC3 while the engine switch off, and turn a door courtesy light switch on and off at 1.5-second intervals until communication between the tester and vehicle begins.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>PRECAUTIONS FOR EACH FUNCTION</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Precautions for the electrical key:</ptxt>
<list1 type="nonmark">
<item>
<ptxt>The electrical key is a precision instrument. Be sure to observe the following:</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<step3>
<ptxt>Do not drop or strike the electrical key.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Do not allow the electrical key to be kept in a high temperature place for a long time.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Do not use an ultrasonic washing machine to clean the electrical key.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Keep the electrical key away from magnets or magnetized items during use.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Do not attach any stickers to the electrical key.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Precautions for the engine start function:</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Before starting the engine, firmly depress the brake pedal until the indicator of the engine switch illuminates in green.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Be sure to turn the engine switch off before disconnecting the negative (-) battery terminal. When the battery terminal is disconnected, the power source mode (off, on (ACC), on (IG)) will remain in memory. When the vehicle's battery becomes discharged, be careful to remember the power source mode.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>After the battery is removed and reinstalled, be sure to wait 10 seconds or more before the next engine start. The engine may not start immediately after the battery is reinstalled.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Precautions for the battery built into the electrical key and the vehicle battery:</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>When the doors are locked (locked state), signals are emitted by the vehicle at a predetermined interval. If the vehicle were to remain parked for a long time, the vehicle battery could become discharged. To prevent this, periodically charge the vehicle battery, or disable the entry and start system.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>When the doors are locked (locked state), and the electrical key remains in the door oscillator detection area, the system will maintain periodic communication with the electrical key. If the vehicle remains parked in this state for a long time, the vehicle and key batteries could become discharged. If the vehicle is not being used, keep the electrical key at least 2 m (6.56 ft) from the vehicle.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
</step1>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>