<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="T1">
<name>INTRODUCTION</name>
<section id="10002_S000B" variety="S000B">
<name>INTRODUCTION</name>
<ttl id="10002_S000B_730EQ_T00F2" variety="T00F2">
<name>REPAIR INSTRUCTION</name>
<para id="RM000000UYY01JX" category="F" type-id="30022" name-id="IN01H-14" from="200601">
<name>VEHICLE LIFT AND SUPPORT LOCATIONS</name>
<subpara id="RM000000UYY01JX_z0" proc-id="RM0250U___00009Z500000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<step1>
<ptxt>NOTICE ABOUT VEHICLE CONDITION WHEN JACKING UP</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>As a rule, the vehicle must be unloaded when jacking up. Never jack up or lift up the vehicle loaded with things of heavy weight.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>When removing any parts of heavy weight like the engine and transaxle, the center of gravity of the vehicle moves. Place a balance weight so as to keep it from rolling, or hold the jacking support location using the mission jack.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>NOTICE FOR USING 4 POST LIFT</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Follow the instruction manual for a safety operation.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Do not damage tires or wheels with a free wheel beam.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Using a wheel stopper, fix the vehicle.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>NOTICE FOR USING JACK AND SAFETY STAND</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Work in the flat place using a wheel stopper at all times.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Use a safety stand with a rubber attachment, as shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="D025082E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Support the specified location with a jack and safety stand accurately.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>When jacking up the front wheels, release the parking brake and place wheel stoppers only behind the rear wheels. When jacking up the rear wheels, place wheel stoppers only in front of the front wheels.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Do not work or leave the vehicle supported only by a jack. Be sure to support the vehicle with a safety stand.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>When jacking up only the front wheels or only the rear wheels, place wheel stoppers to both sides of the wheels that contact ground.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>When jacking down the vehicle with its front wheels jacked up, release the parking brake and place wheel stoppers only in front of the rear wheels. When jacking down the vehicle with its rear wheels jacked up, place wheel stoppers only behind the front wheels.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="D101408E02" width="7.106578999in" height="5.787629434in"/>
</figure>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>NOTICE FOR USING SWING ARM TYPE LIFT</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Follow the instruction manual of the lift for a safety operation.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Use a cradle with a rubber attachment, as shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Set in the vehicle so as to make its center of gravity as close as possible to the center of the lift.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Place the vehicle horizontally by adjusting the height of the cradle, and match the groove of the cradle and the safety stand support location accurately.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Be sure to lock the swing arm during the operation.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Lift the vehicle up until the tires float, and shake the vehicle to make sure that the vehicle is stable.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>NOTICE FOR USING PLATE TYPE LIFT</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Follow the instruction manual of the lift for a safety operation.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Use a plate lift attachment.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Be sure to set the vehicle to the specified position.</ptxt>
<table pgwide="1">
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="COL1" colwidth="3.54in"/>
<colspec colname="COL2" colwidth="3.54in"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Right and left set position</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Place the vehicle over the center of the lift.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Front and rear set position</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Align the cushion gum ends of the plate with the attachment lower ends (A and C).</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Align the attachment upper end (B) with the rocker flange front side notch.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Lift the vehicle up until the tires float a bit, and shake the vehicle to make sure that the vehicle is stable.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="D100367E01" width="7.106578999in" height="7.795582503in"/>
</figure>
</step2>
</step1>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>