<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="37">
<name>STEERING</name>
<section id="1000U_S0013" variety="S0013">
<name>STEERING COLUMN</name>
<ttl id="1000U_S0013_72VA7_T004F" variety="T004F">
<name>STEERING SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM000001R44002X" category="N" type-id="3000G" name-id="SR0CM-03" from="200601">
<name>ADJUSTMENT</name>
<subpara id="RM000001R44002X_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM000001R44002X_01_0001" proc-id="RM0250U___00000KY00000">
<ptxt>STEERING OFF CENTER ADJUSTMENT PROCEDURE</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<atten4>
<ptxt>This is the adjustment procedure for steering off center.</ptxt>
</atten4>
<s2>
<ptxt>Inspect steering wheel off center.</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>Apply masking tape on the top center of the steering wheel and steering column upper cover.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C132538E01" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Drive the vehicle in a straight line for 100 meters at a constant speed of 35 mph (56 km/h), and hold the steering wheel to maintain the course.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Draw a line on the masking tape as shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C132539E01" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Turn the steering wheel to the center position.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Look at the upper surface of the steering wheel, steering spoke, and SRS airbag line to find the center position.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Draw a new line on the masking tape on the steering wheel as shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C132540E01" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Measure the distance between the 2 lines on the masking tape on the steering wheel.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Convert the measured distance to steering angle.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Measured distance 1 mm (0.04 in.) = Steering angle of approximately 1 degree.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Make a note of the steering angle.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten4>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Adjust steering angle.</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>Draw a line on the RH and LH tie rod ends and rack ends respectively where it can be easily seen.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C132045E02" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Using a paper gauge, measure the distance from the RH and LH tie rod ends to the rack end screws.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Measure both the RH and LH sides.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Make a note of the measured values.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten4>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Remove the RH and LH boot clips from the rack boots.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C132541" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Loosen the RH and LH lock nuts.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Turn the RH and LH rack ends by the same amount (but in different directions) according to the steering angle.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>One 360 degree turn of the rack end (1.5 mm (0.059 in.) horizontal movement) equals to 12 degrees of steering angle.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Tighten the RH and LH lock nuts to the specified torque.</ptxt>
<torque>
<torqueitem>
<t-value1>74</t-value1>
<t-value2>755</t-value2>
<t-value4>55</t-value4>
</torqueitem>
</torque>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Make sure that the difference in length between the RH and LH tie rod ends and rack end screws is within 1.5 mm (0.059 in.).</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Install the RH and LH boot clips.</ptxt>
</s3>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>