<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="30">
<name>ENGINE</name>
<section id="1000C_S000M" variety="S000M">
<name>2GR-FE COOLING</name>
<ttl id="1000C_S000M_72Z7G_T00B4" variety="T00B4">
<name>COOLING SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM000000V1Q011X" category="G" type-id="8000T" name-id="CO0J5-03" from="200601">
<name>ON-VEHICLE INSPECTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000000V1Q011X_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM000000V1Q011X_01_0001" proc-id="RM0250U___000063Y00000">
<ptxt>CHECK FOR ENGINE COOLANT LEAKS</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<atten2>
<ptxt>Do not remove the radiator cap while the engine and radiator are still hot. Pressurized, hot engine coolant and steam may be released and cause serious burns.</ptxt>
</atten2>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Before performing each inspection, turn the A/C switch OFF.</ptxt>
</atten3>
<s2>
<ptxt>Fill the radiator with coolant and attach a radiator cap tester.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A133894" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Warm up the engine.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Using a radiator cap tester, increase the pressure inside the radiator to 118 kPa (1.2 kgf*cm, 17 psi), and check that the pressure does not drop.</ptxt>
<ptxt>If the pressure drops, check the hoses, radiator and water pump for leaks. If no external leaks are found, check the heater core, cylinder block and cylinder head.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000000V1Q011X_01_0002" proc-id="RM0250U___000063Z00000">
<ptxt>INSPECT ENGINE COOLANT LEVEL IN RESERVOIR</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Check that the engine coolant level is between the LOW and FULL lines when the engine is cold. </ptxt>
<ptxt>If the engine coolant level is low, check for leaks and add "TOYOTA Super Long Life Coolant" or similar high quality ethylene glycol based non-silicate, non-amine, non-nitrite and non-borate coolant with long-life hybrid organic acid technology to the FULL line. </ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Do not substitute plain water for engine coolant.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000000V1Q011X_01_0003" proc-id="RM0250U___000064000000">
<ptxt>INSPECT ENGINE COOLANT QUALITY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Remove the radiator cap.</ptxt>
<atten2>
<ptxt>Do not remove the radiator cap while the engine and radiator are still hot. Pressurized, hot engine coolant and steam may be released and cause serious burns.</ptxt>
</atten2>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Check if there are any excessive deposits of rust or scales around the radiator cap and radiator filler hole. Also, the coolant should be free of oil.</ptxt>
<ptxt>If excessively dirty, clean the coolant passage and replace the coolant.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the radiator cap.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>