<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="39">
<name>RESTRAINTS</name>
<section id="1000Y_S0016" variety="S0016">
<name>SUPPLEMENTAL RESTRAINT SYSTEM</name>
<ttl id="1000Y_S0016_72ZS3_T00CJ" variety="T00CJ">
<name>AIRBAG SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM000000XFE00YX" category="D" type-id="303F4" name-id="RS064-35" from="200601">
<name>DTC CHECK / CLEAR</name>
<subpara id="RM000000XFE00YX_z0" proc-id="RM0250U___000072200000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<step1>
<ptxt>DTC CHECK (USING SST CHECK WIRE)</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Check the DTCs (Present trouble code).</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A082779E07" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<step3>
<ptxt>Turn the ignition switch on (IG), and wait for approximately 60 seconds.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Using SST, connect terminals TC and CG of the DLC3.</ptxt>
<sst>
<sstitem>
<s-number>09843-18040</s-number>
</sstitem>
</sst>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Connect the terminals to the correct positions to avoid a malfunction.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Check the DTCs (Past trouble code).</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Using SST, connect terminals TC and CG of the DLC3.</ptxt>
<sst>
<sstitem>
<s-number>09843-18040</s-number>
</sstitem>
</sst>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Connect the terminals to the correct positions to avoid a malfunction.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Turn the ignition switch on (IG), and wait for approximately 60 seconds.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Read the DTCs.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="H013050E17" width="2.775699831in" height="4.7836529in"/>
</figure>
<step3>
<ptxt>Read the blinking patterns of the DTCs. As examples, the blinking patterns for the normal system code and trouble codes 11 and 31 are shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Normal system code indication (without past trouble code)</ptxt>
<ptxt>The light blinks twice per second.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Normal system code indication (with past trouble code)</ptxt>
<ptxt>When the past trouble code is stored in the center airbag sensor assembly, the light blinks only once per second.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Trouble code indication</ptxt>
<ptxt>The first blinks indicates the first DTC. The second blinks occurs after a 1.5-second pause.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<ptxt>If there are more than 1 code, there will be a 2.5-second pause between each code. After all codes are shown, there will be a 4.0-second pause, and then they will all be repeated.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>If 2 or more malfunctions are found, the indication begins with the smaller numbered code.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If DTCs are indicated without connecting the terminals, proceed to "Diagnosis Circuit" (See page <xref label="Seep01" href="RM0000014JK00GX"/>).</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten4>
</step3>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DTC CLEAR (USING SST CHECK WIRE)</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Clear the DTCs.</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>When the ignition switch is turned off, the DTCs are cleared.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Depending on the DTC, the code may not be cleared by turning off the ignition switch. In this case, proceed to the next procedure.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Using SST, connect terminals TC and CG of the DLC3, and then turn the ignition switch on (IG).</ptxt>
<sst>
<sstitem>
<s-number>09843-18040</s-number>
</sstitem>
</sst>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Disconnect terminal TC of the DLC3 within 3 to 10 seconds after the DTCs are output, and check if the SRS warning light comes on after 3 seconds.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Within 2 to 4 seconds after the SRS warning light comes on, connect terminals TC and CG of the DLC3.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>The SRS warning light should go off within 2 to 4 seconds after connecting terminals TC and CG of the DLC3. Then, disconnect terminal TC within 2 to 4 seconds after the SRS warning light goes off.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>The SRS warning light comes on again within 2 to 4 seconds after disconnecting terminal TC. Then, reconnect terminals TC and CG within 2 to 4 seconds after the SRS warning light comes on.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Check if the SRS warning light goes off within 2 to 4 seconds after connecting terminals TC and CG of the DLC3. Also check if the normal system code is output within 1 second after the SRS warning light goes off.</ptxt>
<ptxt>If DTCs are not cleared, repeat this procedure until the codes are cleared.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C123780E02" width="7.106578999in" height="4.7836529in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DTC CHECK</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Check the DTCs.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C131977E01" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
<step3>
<ptxt>Connect the intelligent tester to the DLC3.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Turn the ignition switch on (IG).</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Check the DTCs by following the prompts on the tester screen.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Refer to the intelligent tester operator's manual for further details.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Clear the DTCs.</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Connect the intelligent tester to the DLC3.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Turn the ignition switch on (IG).</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Clear the DTCs by following the prompts on the tester screen.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Refer to the intelligent tester operator's manual for further details.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</step3>
</step2>
</step1>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>