<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="36">
<name>BRAKE</name>
<section id="1002J_S0010" variety="S0010">
<name>BRAKE CONTROL</name>
<ttl id="1002J_S0010_72W30_T005W" variety="T005W">
<name>VEHICLE STABILITY CONTROL SYSTEM (for BOSCH Made)</name>
<para id="RM000001NJE001X" category="L" type-id="3001A" name-id="BC12U-02" from="200601">
<name>PRECAUTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000001NJE001X_z0" proc-id="RM0250U___000012G00000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<step1>
<ptxt>EXPRESSIONS OF IGNITION SWITCH</ptxt>
<ptxt>The type of ignition switch used on this model differs according to the specifications of the vehicle.</ptxt>
<ptxt>The expressions listed in the table below are used in this section.</ptxt>
<table pgwide="1">
<tgroup cols="3">
<colspec colname="COL1" colwidth="2.36in"/>
<colspec colname="COL2" colwidth="2.36in"/>
<colspec colname="COL3" colwidth="2.36in"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry morerows="1" valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Expression</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry namest="COL2" nameend="COL3" valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Switch Type</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Ignition Switch (Position)</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Engine Switch (Condition)</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Ignition switch off</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>LOCK</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>off</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Ignition switch on (IG)</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>ON</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>on (IG)</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Ignition switch on (ACC)</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>ACC</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>on (ACC)</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Engine start</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>START</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>start</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>TROUBLESHOOTING PRECAUTION</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>When there is a malfunction in the contact point of the terminals or installation problems with parts, the removal and installation of the suspected problem parts may return the system to the normal condition either completely or temporarily.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>In order to determine the malfunctioning area, be sure to check the conditions at the time the malfunction occurred, such as by DTC output and freeze frame data output, and record it before disconnecting each connector or removing and installing parts.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Since the vehicle stability control system may be influenced by a malfunction in the other systems, be sure to check for DTCs in the other systems.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Be sure to remove and install the brake actuator assembly and each sensor with the ignition switch off unless specified in the inspection procedure.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>If the brake actuator or a sensor has been removed and installed, it is necessary to check the system for problems after the parts have been reassembled. Check for DTCs using the intelligent tester, also check that system functions and signals received by the ECU are normal using test mode.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>CAN COMMUNICATION SYSTEM PRECAUTION</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>The CAN communication system is used for data communication between the skid control ECU, the steering angle sensor, and the yaw rate and acceleration sensor. If there is trouble in the CAN communication line, a DTC of the communication line is output.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>If a DTC of the CAN communication line is output, repair the malfunction in the communication line and troubleshoot the vehicle stability control system under the condition that data communication is normal.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>In order to enable CAN communication, a specific type of wiring is used for the CAN communication lines. The wiring used for each communication line is a twisted pair of wires that have an equal length. A bypass wire should not be used, because the data being transmitted will be corrupted.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DTC PRECAUTION</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Warnings for some DTCs cannot be cleared by only repairing the malfunctioning parts. If the warning is displayed after repair work, the DTC should be cleared after turning the ignition switch off.</ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>If a DTC for a malfunctioning part reappears after it was cleared, then it has been stored again.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>CHASSIS DYNAMOMETER PRECAUTION</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Enter Test Mode to disable TRAC and VSC control when using a chassis dynamometer (See page <xref label="Seep01" href="RM000000UYX01KX"/>).</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>The vehicle may move unexpectedly out of the dynamometer because of TRAC and VSC operations.</ptxt>
</atten4>
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Make sure that the VSC warning (multi information display and master caution indicator light) light is blinking (Inspection Mode is achieved).</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Secure the vehicle with the lock chain for safety.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten3>
</step2>
</step1>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>