<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="30">
<name>ENGINE</name>
<section id="10007_S0005" variety="S0005">
<name>2AZ-FE FUEL</name>
<ttl id="10007_S0005_7305N_T00DK" variety="T00DK">
<name>FUEL SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM000000YCO003X" category="L" type-id="3001A" name-id="FU065-04" from="200601">
<name>PRECAUTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000000YCO003X_z0" proc-id="RM0250U___00008V200000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<step1>
<ptxt>PRECAUTION</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Before inspecting and repairing the fuel system, disconnect the cable from the negative (-) battery terminal.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Do not smoke or work near fire when handling the fuel system.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Keep gasoline away from rubber or leather parts.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DISCHARGE FUEL SYSTEM PRESSURE</ptxt>
<atten2>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Perform the following procedures to prevent fuel from spilling out before removing any fuel system parts.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Pressure will still remain in the fuel line even after performing the following procedures. When disconnecting the fuel line, cover it with a shop rag or a piece of cloth to prevent fuel from spraying or coming out.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Remove the rear seat cushion assembly.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A129607" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Remove the rear floor service hole cover.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Disconnect the fuel pump connector.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Start the engine.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>After the engine stops, turn the ignition switch off.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>DTC P0171/25 (fuel problem) may be detected.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Crank the engine again. Check that the engine does not start.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Remove the fuel tank cap to discharge pressure from the fuel tank.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Disconnect the cable from the negative (-) battery terminal.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Reconnect the fuel pump connector.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Install the rear floor service hole cover.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Install the rear seat.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>FUEL SYSTEM</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>When disconnecting the high fuel pressure line, a large amount of gasoline will spill out, so observe the following procedures:</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Discharge the fuel system pressure. (step 2)</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Disconnect the fuel pump tube (See page <xref label="Seep01" href="RM000001IRA003X_01_0005"/>).</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Drain the fuel that remains in the fuel pump tube.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>To protect the disconnected fuel pump tube from damage and contamination, cover it with a plastic bag.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B000679E07" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Put a container under the connectors.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Observe the following precautions when removing and installing the fuel injectors:</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A131629E01" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
<step3>
<ptxt>Never reuse an O-ring.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>When placing a new O-ring on the injector, do not damage the O-ring.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Coat a new O-ring with gasoline before installing it.</ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Do not use engine oil, gear oil or brake fluid.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Install the injector to the delivery pipe and the cylinder head, as shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A097444E02" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Before installing the injector, be sure to apply appropriate lubricant or gasoline to the place where the delivery pipe or cylinder head contacts the injector O-rings.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Observe the following precautions when disconnecting the fuel delivery pipe (metallic type): </ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A050709E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten4>
<ptxt>The structure of the metallic connector is shown on the left.</ptxt>
</atten4>
<step3>
<ptxt>Remove the No. 2 fuel pipe clamp.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A136248E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten4>
<ptxt>The No. 2 fuel pipe clamp cannot be reused.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Find the metallic connector of the fuel tube assembly.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A130371E01" width="2.775699831in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Assemble SST to the connection as shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
<sst>
<sstitem>
<s-number>09268-21010</s-number>
</sstitem>
</sst>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Turn the SST, align the retainers inside the connector with the SST chamfered parts and insert SST into the connector.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Slide the SST and the connector together towards the fuel tube assembly.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Observe the following precautions when connecting the fuel tube connector (metallic type):</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Check if there is any damage or foreign objects on the connecting part of the pipe.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B084645E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Match the axis of the connector with the axis of the pipe, and push into the connector until the connector makes a "click" sound. If the connection is tight, apply a small amount of fresh engine oil to the tip of the pipe.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>After finishing the connection, check if the pipe and the connector are securely connected by pulling on them.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B084645E04" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Check for fuel leaks.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Install a new No. 2 fuel pipe clamp.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A136248E02" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Observe the following precautions when disconnecting the fuel tube connectors (Quick type A):</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Remove the No. 1 fuel pipe clamp from the tube connector.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A060083E16" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Check that there is no dirt or other foreign objects on the pipe and around the connector before disconnecting them. Clean them if necessary.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Disconnect the connector from the pipe by hand.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A088336E10" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>If the connector and the pipe are stuck, push in and pull on the connector to release it. Pull the connector out of the pipe carefully.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Check that there is no dirt or other foreign objects on the sealing surface of the disconnected pipe. Clean the surfaces if necessary.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Do not damage the disconnected pipe or connector. Prevent entry of foreign objects by covering the connectors with plastic bags.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B009222E04" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Observe the following precautions when connecting the fuel tube connectors (Quick Type A):</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A121423E01" width="2.775699831in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
<step3>
<ptxt>Check if there is any damage or foreign objects on the connecting parts of the pipes.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Line up the two parts of the pipes to be connected, and push them together until the connector makes a "click" sound. If the pipe is difficult to push into the connector, apply a small amount of clean engine oil to the tip of the pipe and reinsert it.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>After connecting the pipes, check that the pipe and connector are securely connected by pulling on them.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Check for fuel leaks.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Observe the following precautions when disconnecting the fuel tube connector (Quick type B):</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A129459E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<step3>
<ptxt>Before disconnecting the connector, clean off any dirt that may be present.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Pinch the tabs of the fuel tube retainer to disengage the 2 claws. Push the retainer down as shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Be sure to disconnect the connector by hand.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>If the connector and pipe are stuck, hold the fuel pipe by hand and push and pull on the connector. Pull the two pipes apart to separate the connector.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A091246E06" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Check if there is any dirt or any other foreign objects on the sealing surfaces of the disconnected pipes. Clean the sealing surfaces if necessary.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Do not damage the disconnected pipe or connector. Prevent entry of foreign objects by covering the connectors with plastic bags.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A093309E03" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Observe the following precautions when connecting the fuel tube connector (Quick Type B):</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Line up the two parts of the pipes to be connected, and fully push the fuel tube connector and pipe together until they are fully seated. Next, push the retainer into the connector until its claws lock. If the pipe is difficult to push in to the connector, apply a small amount of clean engine oil to the tip of the pipe and reinsert it.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="A132390E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>After connecting the pipes, check that the pipe and connector are securely connected by pulling on them.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Check for fuel leaks.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Observe the following precautions when handling a nylon tube:</ptxt>
<atten2>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Do not twist the connector part of the nylon tube or the quick connector when connecting them.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not bend or twist the nylon tube.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not remove the EPDM protector on the outside of the nylon tube.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not pinch or kink the nylon tubes to prevent fuel leakage.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten2>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>CHECK FOR FUEL LEAKS</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Check that there are no fuel leaks from the fuel system after doing any maintenance or repairs (See page <xref label="Seep02" href="RM000000YCR002X"/>).</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>