<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="42">
<name>BODY ELECTRICAL</name>
<section id="1001A_S001B" variety="S001B">
<name>LIGHTING</name>
<ttl id="1001A_S001B_72Y3J_T008C" variety="T008C">
<name>FOG LIGHT ASSEMBLY</name>
<para id="RM0000011MP007X" category="N" type-id="3000G" name-id="LI26H-01" from="200601">
<name>ADJUSTMENT</name>
<subpara id="RM0000011MP007X_02" type-id="11" category="10" proc-id="RM0250U___0000C7400000">
<content3 releasenbr="1">
<atten4>
<ptxt>It is possible that a bulb is incorrectly installed, affecting fog light aim. Bulb installation should be considered prior to performing the adjustment procedure.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</content3>
</subpara>
<subpara id="RM0000011MP007X_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM0000011MP007X_01_0001" proc-id="RM0250U___00003DW00000">
<ptxt>VEHICLE PREPARATION FOR FOG LIGHT AIM ADJUSTMENT</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Prepare the vehicle according to the following conditions:</ptxt>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Ensure there is no damage or deformation to the body around the fog lights.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Fill the fuel tank.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Make sure that the oil is filled to the specified level.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Make sure that the coolant is filled to the specified level.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Inflate the tires to the appropriate pressure.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Unload the trunk and vehicle, ensuring that the spare tire, tools, and jack are in their original positions.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Sit a person of average weight (68 kg, 150 lb) in the driver's seat.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Vehicles with height adjustable suspension should set the vehicle height to the lowest setting prior to adjusting the fog light aim.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011MP007X_01_0002" proc-id="RM0250U___00003DX00000">
<ptxt>PREPARATION FOR FOG LIGHT AIMING</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Prepare the vehicle:</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="E128202E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Place the vehicle in a location that is dark enough to clearly observe the cutoff line. The cutoff line is a distinct line, below which light from the fog lights can be observed and above which it cannot.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Place the vehicle at a 90° angle to the wall.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Create a 7.62 m (25 ft) distance between the vehicle (fog light bulb center) and the wall.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Make sure that the vehicle is on a level surface.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Bounce the vehicle up and down to settle the suspension.</ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>A distance of 7.62 m (25 ft) between the vehicle (fog light bulb center) and the wall is necessary for proper aim adjustment. If unavailable, secure a distance of exactly 3 m (9.84 ft) for check and adjustment. (The target zone will change with the distance, so follow the instructions in the illustration.)</ptxt>
</atten3>
</item>
</list1>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Prepare a piece of thick white paper (approximately 2 m  (6.6 ft) (height) x 4 m (13.1 ft) (width)) to use as a screen.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Draw a vertical line down the center of the screen (V line).</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Set the screen as shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="E128203E01" width="7.106578999in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
<atten4>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Stand the screen perpendicular to the ground.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Align the V line on the screen with the center of the vehicle.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten4>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Draw base lines (H, V LH, and V RH lines) on the screen as shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="I033423E15" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Mark the fog light bulb center marks on the screen. If the center mark cannot be observed on the fog light, use the center of the fog light bulb or the manufacturer's name marked on the fog light as the center mark.</ptxt>
</atten4>
<s3>
<ptxt>H Line (Fog light height):</ptxt>
<ptxt>Draw a horizontal line across the screen so that it passes through the center marks. The H line should be at the same height as the fog light bulb center marks of the low-beam fog lights.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>V LH Line, V RH Line (Center mark position of left-hand (LH) and right-hand (RH) fog lights):</ptxt>
<ptxt>Draw two vertical lines so that they intersect the H line at each center mark.</ptxt>
</s3>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011MP007X_01_0003" proc-id="RM0250U___00003DY00000">
<ptxt>FOG LIGHT AIMING INSPECTION</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Cover the fog light or disconnect the connector of the fog light on the opposite side to prevent light from the fog light that is not being inspected from affecting the fog light aiming inspection.</ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Do not keep the fog light covered for more than 3 minutes. The fog light lens is made of synthetic resin, which may melt or be damaged due to excessive heat.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Start the engine.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Turn on the fog light and check if the cut off line falls within the specified area in the following illustration.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="I041221E02" width="7.106578999in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011MP007X_01_0004" proc-id="RM0250U___00003DZ00000">
<ptxt>FOG LIGHT AIMING ADJUSTMENT</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Adjust the aim vertically:</ptxt>
<ptxt>Adjust the aim of each fog light to the specified range by turning each aiming screw with a screwdriver.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="E128204E01" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
<atten3>
<ptxt>The final turn of the aiming screw should be made in the clockwise direction. If the screw is tightened excessively, loosen it and then retighten it, so that the final turn of the screw is in the clockwise direction.</ptxt>
</atten3>
<atten4>
<ptxt>If it is not possible to correctly adjust fog light aim, check bulb, fog light unit, and fog light unit reflector installation.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>