<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="43">
<name>BODY</name>
<section id="1002Z_S001S" variety="S001S">
<name>SLIDING ROOF</name>
<ttl id="1002Z_S001S_732XN_T00GB" variety="T00GB">
<name>SLIDING ROOF SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM000000UZX00IX" category="G" type-id="8000T" name-id="RF07C-01" from="200601">
<name>ON-VEHICLE INSPECTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000000UZX00IX_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM000000UZX00IX_01_0001" proc-id="RM0250U___0000BGA00000">
<ptxt>CHECK AUTO OPERATION</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Turn the ignition switch on (IG).</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the roof glass is fully closed, press the OPEN switch for 0.3 seconds or more. Check that the roof glass automatically slides until it is fully opened.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the roof glass is fully open, press the CLOSE switch for 0.3 seconds or more. Check that the roof glass automatically slides until it is fully closed.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the roof glass is fully closed, press the UP switch for 0.3 seconds or more. Check that the roof glass automatically tilts until it is fully tilted upward.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the roof glass is fully open, press the DOWN switch for 0.3 seconds or more. Check that the roof glass automatically tilts until it is fully tilted downward.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the auto operation is operating, check that pressing any personal light switch stops the roof glass operation.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>When pressing the switch for 0.3 seconds or less, the roof glass moves but auto operation does not operate.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000000UZX00IX_01_0002" proc-id="RM0250U___0000BGB00000">
<ptxt>CHECK SLIDING ROOF OPERATION AFTER IGNITION SWITCH IS TURNED OFF</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Turn the ignition switch from on (IG) to off, and check that the sliding roof operates. Then open and close the driver's side door once, and check that the sliding roof does not operate.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Turn the ignition switch from on (IG) to off and wait for approximately 43 seconds. Check that the sliding roof does not operate.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Operate the auto (SLIDE OPEN/CLOSE or TILT UP/DOWN) operation. While the roof glass is in motion, turn the ignition switch from on (IG) to off. Check that the auto operation continues until the roof glass opens or closes fully.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000000UZX00IX_01_0003" proc-id="RM0250U___0000BGC00000">
<ptxt>CHECK JAM PROTECTION FUNCTION</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<atten2>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Do not use a part of your body, for example, your hand, to check the jam protection.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not allow anything to become caught in the sliding roof by accident in this procedure. </ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Perform the inspection from the inside of the vehicle.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten2>
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Do not use hard objects such as a hammer, to avoid damage to the roof.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If the jam protection does not operate, reset the sliding roof drive gear (motor).</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten3>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the sliding roof auto operation is operating and an object is caught between the vehicle body and glass, check that the roof glass opens 218 mm (8.58 in.) from the point of contact with the object, or opens fully if there is not an opening distance of 218 mm (8.58 in.).</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B068295" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the TILT UP/DOWN function is operating, and an object is caught between the vehicle body and the roof glass, check that the sliding roof tilts up fully.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B068296" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>