<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="39">
<name>RESTRAINTS</name>
<section id="1000Y_S0016" variety="S0016">
<name>SUPPLEMENTAL RESTRAINT SYSTEM</name>
<ttl id="1000Y_S0016_72V8T_T003Q" variety="T003Q">
<name>FRONT PASSENGER AIRBAG ASSEMBLY</name>
<para id="RM000000UXB00IX" category="G" type-id="8000T" name-id="RS05S-18" from="200601">
<name>ON-VEHICLE INSPECTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000000UXB00IX_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM000000UXB00IX_01_0001" proc-id="RM0250U___000002K00000">
<ptxt>INSPECT FRONT PASSENGER AIRBAG ASSEMBLY (VEHICLE NOT INVOLVED IN COLLISION)</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Perform a diagnostic system check (See page <xref label="Seep01" href="RM000000XFD00ZX"/>).</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>With the front passenger airbag assembly installed on the vehicle, perform a visual check. If there are any defects as mentioned below, replace the instrument panel with a new one:</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C132562" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<list1 type="nonmark">
<item>
<ptxt>Cuts, minute cracks or marked discoloration on the instrument panel around the front passenger airbag assembly.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000000UXB00IX_01_0002" proc-id="RM0250U___000002L00000">
<ptxt>INSPECT FRONT PASSENGER AIRBAG ASSEMBLY (VEHICLE INVOLVED IN COLLISION AND AIRBAG HAS NOT DEPLOYED)</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Perform a diagnostic system check (See page <xref label="Seep01" href="RM000000XFD00ZX"/>).</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>With the front passenger airbag assembly removed from the vehicle, perform a visual check. If there are any defects as mentioned below, replace the front passenger airbag assembly, instrument panel or instrument panel reinforcement with a new one:</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C132563" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Cuts, minute cracks or marked discoloration on the front passenger airbag assembly.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Cracks or other damage to the connectors.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Deformation or cracks on the instrument panel or instrument panel reinforcement.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<atten2>
<ptxt>Be sure to follow the correct removal and installation procedures.</ptxt>
</atten2>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>