<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="30">
<name>ENGINE</name>
<section id="10006_S000F" variety="S000F">
<name>2GR-FE ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM</name>
<ttl id="10006_S000F_72XLU_T0075" variety="T0075">
<name>SFI SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM000000PDC01SX" category="D" type-id="303HX" name-id="ES065-53" from="200601">
<name>DEFINITION OF TERMS</name>
<subpara id="RM000000PDC01SX_z0" proc-id="RM0250U___00002EM00000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<table pgwide="1">
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="COL1" colwidth="2.53in"/>
<colspec colname="COL2" colwidth="4.55in"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry align="center">
<ptxt>Terms</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry align="center">
<ptxt>Definition</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Monitor Description</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Description of what ECM monitors and how to detect malfunctions (monitoring purpose and its details).</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Related DTCs</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>A group of diagnostic trouble codes that are output by ECM based on the same malfunction detection logic.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Typical Enabling Condition</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Preconditions that allow ECM to detect malfunctions.</ptxt>
<ptxt>With all preconditions satisfied, ECM sets DTC when monitored value(s) exceeds malfunction threshold(s).</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Sequence of Operation</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Order of monitor priority, applied if multiple sensors and components are involved in single malfunction detection process.</ptxt>
<ptxt>Each sensor and component monitored in turn and not monitored until previous detection operation is completed.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Required Sensor/Components</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Sensors and components used by ECM to detect each malfunction.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Frequency of Operation</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Number of times ECM checks for each malfunction during each driving cycle.</ptxt>
<ptxt>"Once per driving cycle" means that ECM checks for malfunctions only once in single driving cycle.</ptxt>
<ptxt>"Continuous" means that ECM checks for malfunctions whenever enabling conditions are met.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Duration</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Minimum time for which ECM must detect continuous deviation in monitored value(s) in order to set DTC. Timing begins when Typical Enabling Conditions are met.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Malfunction Thresholds</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Value, beyond which, ECM determines malfunctions exist and sets DTCs.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>MIL Operation</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Timing of MIL illumination after a malfunction is detected. </ptxt>
<ptxt>"Immediate" means that ECM illuminates MIL as soon as a malfunction is detected.</ptxt>
<ptxt>"2 driving cycle" means that ECM illuminates MIL if the same malfunction is detected twice during next sequential driving cycle.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>