<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="39">
<name>RESTRAINTS</name>
<section id="1000Z_S0017" variety="S0017">
<name>SEAT BELT</name>
<ttl id="1000Z_S0017_72ZX3_T00CP" variety="T00CP">
<name>SEAT BELT WARNING SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM000001OKS003X" category="G" type-id="8000T" name-id="SB09P-03" from="200601">
<name>ON-VEHICLE INSPECTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000001OKS003X_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM000001OKS003X_01_0004" proc-id="RM0250U___00007YS00000">
<ptxt>INSPECT DRIVER SIDE SEAT BELT WARNING</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Turn the ignition switch on (IG).</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the driver seat belt is not fastened, check that the driver seat belt warning light on the combination meter blinks.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the driver seat belt is fastened, check that the driver seat belt warning light on the combination meter is off.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000001OKS003X_01_0005" proc-id="RM0250U___00007YT00000">
<ptxt>INSPECT PASSENGER SIDE SEAT BELT WARNING</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Turn the ignition switch on (IG).</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the front passenger seat belt is not fastened with the passenger seat occupied, check that the front passenger seat belt warning light on the clock display blinks.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the front passenger seat belt is fastened with the passenger seat occupied, check that the front passenger seat belt warning light on the clock display is off.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000001OKS003X_01_0003" proc-id="RM0250U___00007YR00000">
<ptxt>INSPECT SEAT BELT WARNING BUZZER</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<atten4>
<ptxt>If the buzzer does not sound, the buzzer cancel setting may be set to ON.</ptxt>
</atten4>
<s2>
<ptxt>Turn the ignition switch on (IG).</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the vehicle is driven at approximately 25 km/h (16 mph) or more while the driver or front passenger seat belt is not being fastened, check that the buzzer in the combination meter assembly sounds at an interval of 1.2 seconds for 30 seconds.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Check that the buzzer sounds at an interval of 0.4 seconds for 90 seconds.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Check that the buzzer stops 2 minutes after the buzzer starts sounding.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>After the buzzer has stopped, turn the ignition switch off and then start the engine again. Drive the vehicle at approximately 25 km/h (16 mph) or more while the driver or front passenger seat belt is not being fastened, and then check that the buzzer sounds again.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>After the buzzer has stopped, fasten the driver and front passenger seat belts. Drive the vehicle at approximately 25 km/h (16 mph) or more and unfasten the driver or front passenger seat belt, and then check that the buzzer sounds again.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>After the buzzer has stopped, move the shift lever to the R position, and then move it to the D position. Drive the vehicle at approximately 25 km/h (16 mph) or more, and then check that the buzzer sounds again.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>