<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="43">
<name>BODY</name>
<section id="1002U_S001N" variety="S001N">
<name>WINDSHIELD / WINDOWGLASS</name>
<ttl id="1002U_S001N_72YM9_T00A5" variety="T00A5">
<name>POWER WINDOW CONTROL SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM0000011UZ00AX" category="D" type-id="303F2" name-id="WS03J-09" from="200601">
<name>SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</name>
<subpara id="RM0000011UZ00AX_z0" proc-id="RM0250U___000057A00000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<step1>
<ptxt>POWER WINDOW CONTROL SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>The power window control system controls the power window operation using the power window regulator motors. The main controls of this system are the power window regulator master switch, which is mounted on the driver side door, and the power window regulator switches, which are mounted on the passenger side door and rear doors. Operating a window switch results in electrical power being transmitted to the corresponding power window regulator motor.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>The power window control system has the following functions:</ptxt>
<table pgwide="1">
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="COL1" colwidth="3.55in"/>
<colspec colname="COL2" colwidth="3.53in"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Function</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Outline</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Manual up-and-down function</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>Function that causes window to go up while power window switch is being pulled halfway up and to go down while pushed halfway down. Window stops as soon as the switch is released.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Driver's door auto up-and-down function *</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>Function that enables windows of driver's doors to be fully opened or closed by one press of power window switch.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Jam protection function</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>Function that automatically stops power window and moves it downward if a foreign object gets jammed in door window during auto-up operation.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Remote control function</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>Function that allows power window master switch to control MANUAL up-and-down operations of front passenger door window and rear door windows.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Key-off operation function</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>Function that makes it possible to operate power window for approx. 45 seconds after ignition switch is turned on (ACC) or off, if either front door is not opened.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Key-linked up-and-down function</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>Function that causes window to go up while driver's door key is turned to lock side for more than 1.5 seconds and to go down while turned to unlock side for more than 1.5 seconds. Window stops as soon as the key is returned to original position.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Diagnosis</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>Function that allows the power window switch to make a diagnosis for failed section when power window switch detects a malfunction in power window system. Power window switch light comes on or blinks to inform driver.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>Fail-safe</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>A fail-safe function to disable a part of power window functions if pulse sensor in power window motor has a malfunction:</ptxt>
<ptxt>Driver's door auto up-and-down function and remote control function are disabled.</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<ptxt>*: with Jam Protection</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>