<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="38">
<name>HEATER &amp; AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM</name>
<section id="1002K_S0015" variety="S0015">
<name>AIR CONDITIONING</name>
<ttl id="1002K_S0015_731I1_T00FN" variety="T00FN">
<name>REFRIGERANT</name>
<para id="RM000001146004X" category="A" type-id="30019" name-id="AC2JV-01" from="200601">
<name>REPLACEMENT</name>
<subpara id="RM000001146004X_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM000001146004X_01_0001" proc-id="RM0250U___0000AW600000">
<ptxt>RECOVER REFRIGERANT FROM REFRIGERATION SYSTEM</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Start up the engine.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Turn the A/C switch on.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Operate the cooler compressor at an engine speed of approximately 1,000 rpm for 5 to 6 minutes to circulate the refrigerant. This causes most of the compressor oil from the various components of the A/C system to collect in the A/C compressor.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Stop the engine.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Recover the refrigerant from the A/C system using a refrigerant recovery unit.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000001146004X_01_0002" proc-id="RM0250U___0000AW700000">
<ptxt>CHARGE WITH REFRIGERANT</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Perform vacuum purging using a vacuum pump.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Charge with refrigerant HFC-134a (R134a).</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="I037365E09" width="7.106578999in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
<spec>
<title>Standard</title>
<specitem>
<ptxt>450 to 550 g (15.9 to 19.4 oz.)</ptxt>
</specitem>
</spec>
<sst>
<sstitem>
<s-number>07110-58060</s-number>
<s-subnumber>07117-58060</s-subnumber>
<s-subnumber>07117-58070</s-subnumber>
<s-subnumber>07117-58080</s-subnumber>
<s-subnumber>07117-58090</s-subnumber>
<s-subnumber>07117-78050</s-subnumber>
<s-subnumber>07117-88060</s-subnumber>
<s-subnumber>07117-88070</s-subnumber>
<s-subnumber>07117-88080</s-subnumber>
</sstitem>
</sst>
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Do not turn the A/C on before charging with refrigerant. Doing so will cause the cooler compressor to work without refrigerant, resulting in overheating of the cooler compressor.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Approximately 100 g (3.53 oz.) of refrigerant may need to be charged after bubbles disappear.</ptxt>
<ptxt>The refrigerant amount should be checked by quantity, not with the sight glass.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten3>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Ensure that sufficient refrigerant is available to recharge the system when using a refrigerant recovery unit. Refrigerant recovery units are not always able to recover 100 % of the refrigerant from an A/C system.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000001146004X_01_0003" proc-id="RM0250U___0000AW800000">
<ptxt>WARM UP ENGINE</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Keep the A/C switch on for at least 2 minutes to warm up the compressor.</ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Be sure to warm up the compressor when turning the A/C on after removing and installing the cooler refrigerant lines (including the compressor), to prevent damage to the compressor.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000001146004X_01_0004" proc-id="RM0250U___0000AW900000">
<ptxt>CHECK FOR LEAKAGE OF REFRIGERANT</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>After recharging with refrigerant gas, check for leakage of refrigerant gas using a halogen leak detector.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Carry out the test under the following conditions:</ptxt>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>IG OFF</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Secure good ventilation (the gas leak detector may react to volatile gases which are not refrigerant, such as evaporated gasoline and exhaust gas).</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Repeat the test 2 or 3 times.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Make sure that there is some refrigerant remaining in the refrigeration system.</ptxt>
<ptxt>When the compressor is off: approx. 392 to 588 kPa (4 to 6 kgf/cm<sup>2</sup>, 57 to 85 psi)</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Using a gas leak detector, check for leakage from the refrigerant lines.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="I042222E16" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Bring the gas leak detector close to the drain hose with the detector's power off, and then turn the detector on.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="N014519E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten4>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>After the blower motor has stopped, let the cooling unit stand for more than 15 minutes.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Bring the gas leak detector sensor under the drain hose.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>When bringing the gas leak detector close to the drain hose, make sure that the gas leak detector does not react to volatile gases.</ptxt>
<ptxt>If it is not possible to avoid interference from volatile gases, the vehicle should be lifted up to allow testing.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten4>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>If a gas leak is not detected from the drain hose, remove the blower motor control from the cooling unit. Insert the gas leak detector sensor into the unit and perform the test.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Disconnect the pressure switch connector and leave it for approximately 20 minutes. Bring the gas leak detector close to the pressure switch and perform the test.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>