<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="38">
<name>HEATER &amp; AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM</name>
<section id="1002K_S0015" variety="S0015">
<name>AIR CONDITIONING</name>
<ttl id="1002K_S0015_72YHT_T00A2" variety="T00A2">
<name>COMPRESSOR AND MAGNETIC CLUTCH (for 2GR-FE)</name>
<para id="RM000001OWX002X" category="A" type-id="8000E" name-id="AC1NG-01" from="200601">
<name>REASSEMBLY</name>
<subpara id="RM000001OWX002X_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM000001OWX002X_01_0001" proc-id="RM0250U___00009E300000">
<ptxt>INSTALL MAGNETIC CLUTCH ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the magnetic clutch stator while aligning the protrusion on the stator with the notch on the air compressor assembly as shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="E075075" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Using a snap ring expander, install a new snap ring with the chamfered side facing up.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="I032461E03" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Take care not to damage the seal cover of the bearing when installing the snap ring.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Connect the connector.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Using a snap ring expander, install the magnetic clutch rotor and a new snap ring with the chamfered side facing up.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="I031582E07" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Do not expand the snap ring by more than 35.5 mm (1.39 in.) when installing it.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not damage the seal cover of the bearing when installing the snap ring.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the magnetic clutch washer and magnetic clutch hub.</ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Do not change the combination of the magnetic clutch washers used before disassembly.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Using vise pliers, hold the magnetic clutch hub and install the bolt.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="E075076" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<torque>
<torqueitem>
<t-value1>18</t-value1>
<t-value2>184</t-value2>
<t-value4>13</t-value4>
</torqueitem>
</torque>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Make sure that there is no foreign matter or oil on the compressor shaft, bolt, and clutch hub.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000001OWX002X_01_0002" proc-id="RM0250U___00009E400000">
<ptxt>INSPECT MAGNETIC CLUTCH CLEARANCE</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Set the dial indicator to the magnetic clutch hub.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="E075077" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Connect the battery positive lead to terminal 1 of the magnetic clutch connector, and the negative lead to the ground wire. Turn the magnetic clutch on and off and measure the clearance.</ptxt>
<spec>
<title>Standard clearance</title>
<specitem>
<ptxt>0.26 to 0.60 mm (0.010 to 0.024 in.)</ptxt>
</specitem>
</spec>
<ptxt>If the measured value is not within the standard range, remove the magnetic clutch hub and adjust it with magnetic clutch washers.</ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Adjustment should be performed with 3 or less magnetic clutch washers.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Remove the compressor and magnetic clutch from the vise.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM000001OWX002X_01_0003" proc-id="RM0250U___00009E500000">
<ptxt>ADJUST COMPRESSOR OIL LEVEL</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>When replacing the compressor and magnetic clutch with a new one, gradually discharge the inert gas (helium) from the service valve, and drain the following amount of oil from the new compressor and magnetic clutch before installation.</ptxt>
<spec>
<title>Standard</title>
<specitem>
<ptxt>(Oil capacity inside the new compressor and magnetic clutch: 130 + 15 cc (4.6 + 0.51 fl.oz.) ) - (Remaining oil amount in the removed compressor and magnetic clutch) = (Oil amount to be removed from the new compressor when replacing)</ptxt>
</specitem>
</spec>
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>When checking the compressor oil level, observe the precautions on the cooler removal/installation.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If a new compressor and magnetic clutch is installed without removing some oil, due to the oil remaining in the pipes of the vehicle, the oil amount will be too large. This prevents heat exchange in the refrigerant cycle and causes refrigerant failure.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If the volume of oil remaining in the removed compressor and magnetic clutch is too small, check for oil leakage.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Be sure to use ND-OIL 8 or equivalent for compressor oil.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten3>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>