<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="30">
<name>ENGINE</name>
<section id="10024_S000P" variety="S000P">
<name>2GR-FE STARTING</name>
<ttl id="10024_S000P_7307G_T00ES" variety="T00ES">
<name>SMART KEY SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM000000YED00LX" category="L" type-id="3001A" name-id="ST01O-18" from="200601">
<name>PRECAUTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000000YED00LX_z0" proc-id="RM0250U___00009GT00000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<step1>
<ptxt>EMERGENCY ENGINE START CONTROL</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>If there is a malfunction in the stop light switch or STOP fuse, their signals may not be correctly transmitted to the main body ECU. This may result in the engine not starting even if the engine switch is pressed while the brake pedal is depressed and the shift lever is in the P position.</ptxt>
<ptxt>To activate the starter:</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Turn the engine switch from off to on (ACC).</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Press and hold the engine switch for 15 seconds.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>PRECAUTIONS FOR PUSH-BUTTON START FUNCTION:</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Before starting the engine, firmly depress the brake pedal until the indicator in the engine switch turns green.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>The power source mode (off, on (ACC), on (IG)) is always retained in memory by the vehicle. If the battery is disconnected, the power source mode that was present before disconnection will be restored after the battery is reconnected. Be sure to turn the engine switch off before disconnecting the cable from the negative battery terminal. Be careful if the power source mode of a vehicle with a discharged battery is not known.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>After the battery is reconnected, be sure to wait 10 seconds or more before attempting to start the engine. The engine may not start immediately after the battery is reconnected.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>If the electrical key is held near the engine switch to start the engine when the electrical key battery is depleted, the following warnings will sound:</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt> Driver's door open → closed</ptxt>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>An exit warning will sound if the shift lever is in a position other than P and the power source is in a mode other than off.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>An exit warning will sound if the shift lever is in the P position and the power source is in a mode other than off.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Doors other than the driver door open → closed</ptxt>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>A warning will sound to indicate that the electrical key has been taken out of the vehicle.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</step3>
</step2>
</step1>
<ptxt>These warnings will sound because it is not possible for the vehicle to determine if the key is present in the vehicle (due to the depleted key battery). These warnings do not indicate system malfunctions.</ptxt>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>