<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="42">
<name>BODY ELECTRICAL</name>
<section id="10022_S001G" variety="S001G">
<name>GARAGE DOOR OPENER</name>
<ttl id="10022_S001G_72ZU9_T00CO" variety="T00CO">
<name>GARAGE DOOR OPENER SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM00000277B000X" category="G" type-id="3001K" name-id="GD00Y-01" from="200601">
<name>INSPECTION</name>
<subpara id="RM00000277B000X_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM00000277B000X_01_0001" proc-id="RM0250U___00008KT00000">
<ptxt>INSPECT GARAGE DOOR OPENER</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>To inspect the garage door opener system, press each switch and check that the LED in the "HomeLink" logo illuminates as illustrated. If one or more of the switches do not cause the LED to illuminate, confirm that the fuse and the wiring to the garage door opener system unit is normal. If the fuse and wiring are normal, and the LED does not work, replace the garage door opener system unit located in the roof console box assembly.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="E129941E01" width="2.775699831in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM00000277B000X_01_0002" proc-id="RM0250U___00008KU00000">
<ptxt>INSPECT GARAGE DOOR OPENER REGISTRATION AND TRANSMITTIMG OPERATION</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<atten4>
<ptxt>Use the KENT-MOORE "HomeLink" tester, and the KENT-MOORE handheld transmitter for this test. First erase the customer's transmitter codes, and then register the tester's handheld transmitter code to the garage door opener system.</ptxt>
</atten4>
<s2>
<ptxt>Check if the tester's handheld transmitter code was successfully registered.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="E129943E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten4>
<ptxt>If the handheld transmitter's code cannot be registered, replace the garage door opener system unit.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Press the garage door opener switch that was used to copy the signal from the handheld transmitter. Check if the "HomeLink" tester's green LED illuminates.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="E129944E01" width="2.775699831in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
<atten4>
<ptxt>If the green LED does not illuminate, replace the garage door opener system unit that is located in the roof console box assembly.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>When the inspection is complete, re-register the customer's handheld transmitter codes.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>