<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="36">
<name>BRAKE</name>
<section id="1000N_S0011" variety="S0011">
<name>BRAKE</name>
<ttl id="1000N_S0011_72V8Y_T003V" variety="T003V">
<name>BRAKE MASTER CYLINDER</name>
<para id="RM000000V33004X" category="G" type-id="3001K" name-id="BR02B-05" from="200601">
<name>INSPECTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000000V33004X_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM000000V33004X_01_0001" proc-id="RM0250U___00003C700000">
<ptxt>INSPECT AND ADJUST BRAKE BOOSTER PUSH ROD (for TMMK Made)</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Make an adjustment with no vacuum in the brake booster assembly. (Depress the brake pedal several times with the engine stopped.)</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>The brake booster made by TMC does not need adjustment.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten3>
<atten4>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Adjustment of the brake booster push rod is required when the brake master cylinder sub-assembly is replaced with a new one.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Adjustment is not necessary when the removed brake master cylinder sub-assembly is reused and the brake booster assembly is replaced with a new one.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten4>
<s2>
<ptxt>Apply chalk to the tip of the accessory tool.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>An accessory tool is enclosed with a new brake master cylinder sub-assembly.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Place the accessory tool on the brake booster assembly.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C132707E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Measure the clearance between the brake booster push rod and accessory tool.</ptxt>
<spec>
<title>Standard clearance</title>
<specitem>
<ptxt>0 mm (0 in.)</ptxt>
</specitem>
</spec>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Adjust the clearance in the following cases:</ptxt>
</atten4>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>If there is a clearance between the accessory tool and the shell of the brake booster (floating accessory tool), the push rod is protruding too far.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If the chalk does not stick on the tip of the brake booster push rod, the push rod protrusion is insufficient.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>If the clearance is not as specified, adjust the push rod length by holding the rod using SST and turning the tip of the rod using a socket driver (7 mm, 0.28 in.).</ptxt>
<sst>
<sstitem>
<s-number>09737-00020</s-number>
</sstitem>
</sst>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C132720E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Check the push rod clearance again after adjustment.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>