<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="T1">
<name>INTRODUCTION</name>
<section id="10002_S000B" variety="S000B">
<name>INTRODUCTION</name>
<ttl id="10002_S000B_730ER_T00F3" variety="T00F3">
<name>HOW TO TROUBLESHOOT ECU CONTROLLED SYSTEMS</name>
<para id="RM000000UZ201PX" category="F" type-id="3001Z" name-id="IN00M-29" from="200601">
<name>GENERAL INFORMATION</name>
<subpara id="RM000000UZ201PX_z0" proc-id="RM0250U___00009YZ00000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<list1 type="nonmark">
<item>
<ptxt>A large number of ECU controlled systems are used in the CAMRY. In general, ECU controlled systems are considered to be very intricate, requiring a high level of technical knowledge to troubleshoot. However, most problem checking procedures only involve inspecting the ECU controlled system's circuits one by one. An adequate understanding of the system and a basic knowledge of electricity is enough to perform effective troubleshooting, accurate diagnoses and necessary repairs.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="nonmark">
<item>
<ptxt>FOR USING INTELLIGENT TESTER</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Before using the intelligent tester, read the tester operator's manual thoroughly.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If the tester cannot communicate with the ECU controlled systems when the tester is connected to the DLC3 with the ignition switch on and the tester turned on, there is a problem on the vehicle side or tester side.</ptxt>
</item>
<list3 type="ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>If communication is normal when the tester is connected to another vehicle, inspect the diagnosis data link line (Bus (+) line) or ECU power circuit of the vehicle.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If communication is still not possible when the tester is connected to another vehicle, the problem is probably in the tester itself. Perform the Self Test procedures outlined in the tester operator's manual.</ptxt>
</item>
</list3>
</list2>
</list1>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>