<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM0251U">
<servcat id="43">
<name>BODY</name>
<section id="1001K_S001M" variety="S001M">
<name>ENGINE HOOD / DOOR</name>
<ttl id="1001K_S001M_72XLL_T006W" variety="T006W">
<name>REAR DOOR</name>
<para id="RM0000011RY006X" category="A" type-id="8000E" name-id="ED0MX-01" from="200601">
<name>REASSEMBLY</name>
<subpara id="RM0000011RY006X_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0057" proc-id="RM0250U___0000CGV00000">
<ptxt>REPAIR INSTRUCTION
</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Clean the vehicle body surface.</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>Using a heat light, heat the vehicle body surface.</ptxt>
<spec>
<title>Heating temperature</title>
<table>
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="COL1" colwidth="2.07in"/>
<colspec colname="COL2" colwidth="2.06in"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry align="center">
<ptxt>Item</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry align="center">
<ptxt>Temperature</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Vehicle Body</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry align="center">
<ptxt>40 to 60°C (104 to 140°F)</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</spec>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Do not heat the vehicle body excessively.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Wipe off any tape adhesive residue with cleaner.</ptxt>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Installation temperature</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>When ambient temperature is below 15°C, perform the installation procedure after warming the vehicle body surface (installation surface of the door frame) and tape up to between 20 to 30°C using a heat light. When ambient temperature is above 35°C, cool the vehicle body surface (installation surface of the door frame) and tape down to between 20 to 30°C prior to installation.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>The most appropriate temperature for installing the tape is 25°C.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>When the temperature is low, the tape turns stiff and comes off easily. When the temperature is high, the tape looses elasticity.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten4>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Before installation</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>Remove any roughness of coating and dirt on and around the vehicle body surface where the tape will be installed (installation surface of the door frame). If any roughness or dirt remains when pressing the tape onto the surface, air will be trapped under the tape and result in a poor appearance.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Spray water on the shop floor to settle any dust.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Key points for handling the tape</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>The tape bends and rolls up easily. Store the tape between flat pieces of cardboard or other similar objects and keep it dry and level.</ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Do not bend the tape or leave it in high temperature places.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Key points for installation of the tape (how to use a squeegee and installation procedure for flat surfaces)</ptxt>
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Conduct positioning of the tape with a high accuracy to achieve a neat finish and to avoid peeling.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>The tape cannot be reused because it deforms or does not fit any more after being removed.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten3>
<s3>
<ptxt>To avoid air bubbles, slightly raise the part of the tape that are going to be applied so that its adhesive surface does not touch the vehicle body while applying the tape. Tilt the squeegee at a 40 to 50° (for pressing forward) or 30 to 45° (for pulling) to the vehicle body surface and press the tape onto the vehicle body surface with a force of 20 to 30 N (2 to 3 kgf) at a constant slow speed of 3 to 7 cm per second.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B147252E01" width="7.106578999in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Be sure to observe the specified pressing speed, force, and angle of the squeegee to avoid wrinkles or air bubbles.</ptxt>
</atten3>
<atten4>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Either angle of the squeegee (for pressing forward or for pulling) is acceptable.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Be sure to apply the tape while removing the release paper 10 to 20 mm from the edge of the squeegee.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten4>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Key points for installation of the tape (how to use a squeegee and installation procedure for hemming surfaces)</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>If it is difficult to press the tape, press it in several steps as shown in the illustration. Use your fingers or the padded surface of a squeegee to slowly apply the tape to the hem of the vehicle, especially for a small hem.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B147253E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten4>
<ptxt>When applying the tape to the backside of a hem, remove the release paper and use your fingers or the padded surface of a squeegee.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Key points for installation of the tape (how to use a squeegee and installation procedure for corners)</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>Remove the release paper and apply the tape carefully with your fingers.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Before applying the tape to each corner, heat the tape using a heat light and gradually apply it, to avoid wrinkles on the tape and achieve a neat finish.</ptxt>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Check after installation</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>After completing the application, check if the tape is applied neatly. If the tape is not applied neatly, reapply using new tape.</ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Do not reuse the tape.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s3>
</s2>
</content1></s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0058" proc-id="RM0250U___0000CGW00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR LOWER OUTSIDE STRIPE
</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Refer to the illustration to position the rear door lower outside stripe.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B146670E01" width="7.106578999in" height="4.7836529in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Remove the release paper and apply the stripe.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1></s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0059" proc-id="RM0250U___0000CGX00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR OUTSIDE STRIPE
</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<atten3>
<ptxt>Be sure to install the rear door outside stripe after applying the rear door lower outside stripe.</ptxt>
</atten3>
<s2>
<ptxt>Refer to the illustration to position the rear door outside stripe.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B146671E01" width="7.106578999in" height="4.7836529in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Remove the release paper and apply the stripe.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1></s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0051" proc-id="RM0250U___00005TO00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR UPPER WINDOW FRAME MOULDING
</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door upper window frame moulding to the door frame.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Using an air riveter or hand riveter with a nose piece, install the rear door upper window frame moulding with 7 new rivets.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B105050" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten4>
<ptxt> If the rivet cannot be cut, pull it once and cut it.</ptxt>
</atten4>
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Do not pry the rivet with the riveter, as this will cause damage to the riveter and mandrel.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B125583E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Confirm that the rivets are seated properly against the moulding. Do not tilt the riveter when installing the rivet to the moulding. Do not leave any space between the rivet head and moulding.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B125584E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not leave any space between the moulding and door frame. Firmly hold together the 2 items while installing the rivet.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B125585E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list1>
</atten3>
</s2>
</content1></s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0052" proc-id="RM0250U___00005TP00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR FRONT WINDOW FRAME MOULDING
</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<atten4>
<ptxt>When installing the rear door front window frame moulding, heat the vehicle body and rear door front window frame using a heat light.</ptxt>
</atten4>
<spec>
<title>Heating temperature</title>
<table>
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="COL1" colwidth="2.07in"/>
<colspec colname="COL2" colwidth="2.06in"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry align="center">
<ptxt>Item</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry align="center">
<ptxt>Temperature</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Vehicle Body</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry align="center">
<ptxt>40 to 60°C (104 to 140°F)</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Moulding</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry align="center">
<ptxt>20 to 30°C (68 to 86°F)</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</spec>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Do not heat the vehicle body and rear door window frame moulding excessively.</ptxt>
</atten3>
<s2>
<ptxt>Clean the vehicle body surface.</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>Using a heat light, heat the vehicle body surface.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Remove the double-sided tape from the vehicle body.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Wipe off any tape adhesive residue with cleaner.</ptxt>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Clean the rear door front window frame moulding. (If reusing the rear door front window frame moulding)</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B137011E01" width="2.775699831in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
<s3>
<ptxt>Using a heat light, heat the rear door front window frame moulding.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Remove the double-sided tape from the rear door front window frame moulding.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Wipe off any tape adhesive residue with cleaner.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Apply new double-sided tape to the rear door front window frame moulding.</ptxt>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door front window frame moulding.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B137755" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<s3>
<ptxt>Using a heat light, heat the vehicle body and rear door front window frame moulding.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Remove the release paper from the rear door front window frame moulding.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>After removing the release paper, keep the exposed adhesive free from foreign matter.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Engage the clip and install the rear door front window frame moulding.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B137009" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s3>
</s2>
</content1></s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0053" proc-id="RM0250U___00005V300000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR BELT MOULDING ASSEMBLY
</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the clip and 6 claws, and install the rear door belt moulding assembly.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B137004" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1></s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0007" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NB00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR OUTSIDE HANDLE FRAME SUB-ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Apply MP grease to the sliding parts on the rear door outside handle frame sub-assembly.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the claw to install the rear door outside handle frame sub-assembly.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136486" width="2.775699831in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Using a "TORX" socket wrench (T30), install the rear door outside handle frame sub-assembly with the screw.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0008" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NC00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR REAR OUTSIDE HANDLE PAD</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the 2 claws to install the rear door rear outside handle pad.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136484" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0009" proc-id="RM0250U___00001ND00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR FRONT OUTSIDE HANDLE PAD</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the 3 claws to install the rear door front outside handle pad.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136483" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0010" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NE00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR OUTSIDE HANDLE ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Insert the front end of the rear door outside handle assembly into the rear door outside handle frame.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136482" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<atten3>
<ptxt>If the bellcrank lever is not pulled and held when installing the outside handle, the bellcrank lever will interfere with the outside handle and the release plate will be damaged.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Insert the rear end of the rear door outside handle assembly into the rear door outside handle frame. Next, slide the rear door outside handle assembly toward the front of the vehicle to install it.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0011" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NF00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR OUTSIDE HANDLE COVER</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the claws to install the rear door outside handle cover.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136480" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Using a "TORX" socket wrench (T30), install the rear door outside handle cover with the screw.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136479" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0037" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NV00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR INSIDE LOCKING CABLE ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door inside locking cable assembly.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136478" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the 3 claws.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136477" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0038" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NW00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR LOCK REMOTE CONTROL CABLE ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door lock remote control cable assembly.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136476" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the claw.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136475" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0015" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NG00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR LOCK ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>When reusing the removed rear door lock assembly, replace the door lock wiring harness seal on the connector with a new one.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not allow grease or dust to adhere to the door lock wiring harness seal surface of the connector.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Reusing the door lock wiring harness seal or using a damaged door lock wiring harness seal may cause water intrusion to the connection. This may result in a malfunction of the rear door lock assembly.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten3>
<s2>
<ptxt>Apply MP grease to the sliding parts of the rear door lock assembly.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install a new door lock wiring harness seal to the rear door lock assembly.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Insert the rear door lock assembly to the rear door outside handle release plate, and set it to the rear door panel.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136474" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Make sure that the rear door outside handle frame release plate is securely connected to the rear door lock assembly.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Using a "TORX" socket wrench (T30), install the rear door lock assembly with the 3 screws.</ptxt>
<torque>
<torqueitem>
<t-value1>5.0</t-value1>
<t-value2>51</t-value2>
<t-value3>44</t-value3>
</torqueitem>
</torque>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Connect the connector.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0031" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NR00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR POWER WINDOW REGULATOR MOTOR ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<atten3>
<ptxt>The regulator arm must be below the intermediate position when installing the power window regulator motor.</ptxt>
</atten3>
<s2>
<ptxt>Using a "TORX" driver (T25), install the power window regulator motor assembly with the 3 screws.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B124520" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<torque>
<torqueitem>
<t-value1>5.4</t-value1>
<t-value2>55</t-value2>
<t-value3>48</t-value3>
</torqueitem>
</torque>
<atten4>
<ptxt>The new rear window regulator adopts a self-tapping method. The installation position of the regulator will be threaded when the self-tapping screw is inserted.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0017" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NH00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR WINDOW REGULATOR SUB-ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Apply MP grease to the sliding parts of the rear door window regulator sub-assembly.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the temporary bolt to the rear door window regulator sub-assembly.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136472E02" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Temporarily install the window regulator.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Tighten the 4 bolts in the order shown in the illustration to install the rear door window regulator.</ptxt>
<torque>
<torqueitem>
<t-value1>8.0</t-value1>
<t-value2>82</t-value2>
<t-value3>71</t-value3>
</torqueitem>
</torque>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Connect the connector.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0050" proc-id="RM0250U___00006IR00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR FRAME GARNISH</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the clip and install a new rear door frame garnish.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136882" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0022" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NL00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR GLASS RUN</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door glass run.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136466" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0018" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NI00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR GLASS SUB-ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Slide the rear door glass sub-assembly to install it as shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136471" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0020" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NJ00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR QUARTER WINDOW GLASS</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door quarter window glass to the rear door quarter window weatherstrip.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door quarter window glass together with the rear door quarter window weatherstrip in the direction indicated by the arrow in the illustration.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136469" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0021" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NK00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR LOWER WINDOW FRAME SUB-ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Insert the rear door lower window frame sub-assembly from above.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door glass run to the rear door lower window frame sub-assembly.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door lower window frame sub-assembly with the 2 bolts and screw.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136467" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0004" proc-id="RM0250U___00001N800000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR WEATHERSTRIP</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the 20 clips and install the rear door weatherstrip.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136465" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0005" proc-id="RM0250U___00001N900000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR CHECK ASSEMBLY (for TMC Made)</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door check assembly with the 3 bolts.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136464E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<torque>
<subtitle>Bolt (A)</subtitle>
<torqueitem>
<t-value1>26</t-value1>
<t-value2>265</t-value2>
<t-value4>19</t-value4>
</torqueitem>
<subtitle>Bolt (B)</subtitle>
<torqueitem>
<t-value1>8.0</t-value1>
<t-value2>82</t-value2>
<t-value3>71</t-value3>
</torqueitem>
</torque>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0060" proc-id="RM0250U___0000CVM00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR CHECK ASSEMBLY (for TMMK Made)</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door check assembly with the bolt and 2 nuts.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B146084" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<torque>
<subtitle>Bolt</subtitle>
<torqueitem>
<t-value1>26</t-value1>
<t-value2>265</t-value2>
<t-value4>19</t-value4>
</torqueitem>
<subtitle>Nut</subtitle>
<torqueitem>
<t-value1>8.0</t-value1>
<t-value2>82</t-value2>
<t-value3>71</t-value3>
</torqueitem>
</torque>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0023" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NM00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR SERVICE HOLE COVER</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Apply butyl tape to the rear door panel.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Pass the rear door lock remote control cable, rear door inside locking cable and each connector through a new rear door service hole cover.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B146072E01" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the new rear door service hole cover.</ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>Securely install the rear door service hole cover avoiding wrinkles and air bubbles.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Connect the connector and clamp.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0047" proc-id="RM0250U___00005K500000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR INSIDE PANEL REINFORCE</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Install 4 new grommets.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install a new rear door inside panel reinforce with the 4 screws.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136463" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0026" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NN00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR INNER GLASS WEATHERSTRIP</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the 3 claws to install the rear door inner glass weatherstrip.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B146073" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0048" proc-id="RM0250U___00005K600000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR ARMREST BASE PANEL UPPER</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the 4 claws.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136454" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the rear door armrest base panel upper with the 7 screws.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0028" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NP00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR POWER WINDOW REGULATOR SWITCH ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the 2 claws and install the rear power window regulator switch assembly.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136457" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0042" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NZ00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR INSIDE HANDLE SUB-ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Connect the rear door lock remote control cable and rear door inside locking cable to the rear inside handle.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136460" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the 2 claws and install the rear door inside handle sub-assembly.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136453" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0027" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NO00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR TRIM BOARD SUB-ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the claw to install the No. 1 door scuff plate clamp.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B146074" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Connect each connector.</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the rear door trim board with the 4 clips of the rear door inner glass weatherstrip.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136452" width="2.775699831in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the 7 clips to install the rear door trim board to the rear door panel.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136451" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Install the 3 screws.</ptxt>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0049" proc-id="RM0250U___00005K700000">
<ptxt>INSTALL DOOR ASSIST GRIP COVER</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the 6 claws and install the door assist grip cover.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136448" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0030" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NQ00000">
<ptxt>INSTALL REAR DOOR INSIDE HANDLE BEZEL PLUG</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<s2>
<ptxt>Engage the 3 claws to install the rear door inside handle bezel plug.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B136444" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000011RY006X_01_0034" proc-id="RM0250U___00001NT00000">
<ptxt>INITIALIZE POWER WINDOW CONTROL SYSTEM</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<ptxt>(See page <xref label="Seep01" href="RM0000011V200FX"/>)</ptxt>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>