<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../styles/system/outline.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE system-outline SYSTEM "../../../dtd/outline.dtd">
<system-outline pubno="EM0250U" xml:lang="en"><p/><p>The cruise control system is a constant vehicle speed controller which controls the opening angle of the engine throttle valve by the SW, and allows driving at a constant speed without depressing the accelerator pedal.</p><out-title>Set Operation</out-title><p>When the ON­OFF SW is turned on, the systems starts preparations for cruise control and turns on the indicator light in the combination meter.</p><out-title>Set Speed Control</out-title><p>When the ­ SET SW is operated with the ON­OFF SW turned on during driving, the speed is controlled at a constant speed.</p><out-title>Coast Control</out-title><p>When the ­ SET SW is kept turned on during cruise control driving, the engine control module controls the throttle valve to decelerate the vehicle speed.<br/>Every time the ­ SET SW is turned on instantaneously, the vehicle speed is decelerated by approx. 1.6 km/h.</p><out-title>Accel Control</out-title><p>When the + RES SW is kept turned on during cruise control driving, the engine control module controls the throttle valve to accelerate the vehicle speed.<br/>Every time the + RES SW is turned on instantaneously, the vehicle speed is accelerated by approx. 1.6 km/h.</p><out-title>Resume Control</out-title><p>If the vehicle speed is within the low speed limit (Approx. 40 km/h, 25 mph) when canceling the cruise control, operation of the + RES SW accelerates the vehicle speed and resumes the level before canceling the cruise control.</p><out-title>Manual Cancel Mechanism</out-title><p>If any one of the following signals is input during cruise control driving, the cruise control is canceled.</p><p>*The stop light SW is on</p><p>*The CANCEL SW is turned on</p><p>*The ON­OFF SW is turned off</p><p>*Gear is shifted D position to other positions than D. (A/T)</p><p>*The clutch pedal is depressed. (M/T)</p><out-title>Auto Cancel Function</out-title><p>If any of the following conditions are detected, the cruise control is canceled:</p><p>*Failure in the stop light SW wiring</p><p>*Abnormality in the vehicle speed signal</p><p>*Malfunction  in the electronically controlled throttle parts</p><p>*When the vehicle speed gets slower than the low speed limit.</p><p>*When the vehicle speed falls to 16 km/h less than the set speed.</p><out-title>Overdrive Function</out-title><p>The overdrive may be canceled if the vehicle travels on a upward slope during cruise control driving. When the throttle opening information indicates the hill climbing is finished after the overdrive is canceled, the vehicle returns to overdrive mode again as the overdrive return timer is completed.</p></system-outline>
