<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../styles/system/outline.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE system-outline SYSTEM "../../../dtd/outline.dtd">
<system-outline pubno="EM0250U" xml:lang="en"><p/><out-title>1.ABS Operation</out-title><p>If the brake pedal is depressed suddenly, the ABS controls the hydraulic pressure of the wheel cylinders for all the four wheels to automatically avoid wheel locking and ensure the directional and steering stability of the vehicle. If the brake pedal is depressed suddenly, the skid control ECU controls the solenoids in the actuators using the signals from the sensors to move the brake fluid to the reservoir in order to release the braking pressure applied to the wheel cylinder. If the skid control ECU detects that the fluid pressure in the wheel cylinder is insufficient, the ECU controls the solenoids in the actuators to increase the braking pressure.</p><out-title>2.Traction Control Operation</out-title><p>The traction control system controls the engine torque, the hydraulic pressure of the driving wheel cylinders, slipping of the wheels which may occur at start or acceleration of the vehicle, to ensure an optimal driving power and vehicle stability corresponding to the road conditions.</p><out-title>3.VSC Operation</out-title><p>Unexpected road conditions, vehicle speed, emergency situation, and any other external factors may cause large underôÙ or overôÙsteering of the vehicle. If this occurs, the VSC system automatically controls the engine power and wheel brakes to reduce the underôÙ or overôÙsteering.</p><p>To reduce large overôÙsteering :<br/>If the VSC system determines that the overôÙsteering is large, it activates the brakes for the outer turning wheels depending on the degree of the overôÙsteering to produce the moment toward the outside of the vehicle and reduce the overôÙsteering.  </p><p>To reduce large underôÙsteering :<br/>If the VSC system determines that the underôÙsteering is large, it controls the engine power and activates the rear wheel brakes to reduce the underôÙsteering.</p><out-title>4.Fail Safe Function</out-title><p>If an error occurs in the skid control ECU, sensor signals, and/or actuators, the skid control ECU inhibits the brake actuator control and inputs the error signal to the engine control module. According to the error signal, the brake actuator turns off the solenoid and the engine control module rejects any electronically controlled throttle open request from the VSC system. As a result, the vehicle functions regardless of the ABS, TRAC, and VSC systems.</p></system-outline>
